<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>digital on Health Insights</title>
    <link>https://celebrated-fenglisu-226492.netlify.app/en/tags/digital/</link>
    <description>Recent content in digital on Health Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://celebrated-fenglisu-226492.netlify.app/en/tags/digital/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Therapeutics: Definition, Characterisation &amp; Examples</title>
      <link>https://celebrated-fenglisu-226492.netlify.app/en/blog/digi-thera/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celebrated-fenglisu-226492.netlify.app/en/blog/digi-thera/</guid>
      <description>Picture courtesy of netscribes.com As a novel class of healthcare therapies, the definition of Digital therapeutics (DTx) has evolved since it was first described. Sepah et al. mentioned the term ‘digital therapeutics’ for the first time in their peer-reviewed publication in 2015 and defined it as &amp;ldquo;evidence-based behavioral treatments delivered online that can increase accessibility and effectiveness of healthcare.” (Sepah, Jiang, and Peters, 2015). Since then, other definitions and characterizations have emerged from different quarters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at reimbursement Pathways for Prescription Digital therapeutics</title>
      <link>https://celebrated-fenglisu-226492.netlify.app/en/blog/reimbursement-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://celebrated-fenglisu-226492.netlify.app/en/blog/reimbursement-path/</guid>
      <description>Picture courtesy of ilt-engineering.de Current Reimbursement schemes Like all new health technology, once Digital Therapeutics DTx products receive regulatory approval, they are subject to a health technology assessment (HTA). This assessment is critical to help inform decisions on its use and reimbursement status based on the added value and position in the care continuum. &amp;ldquo;HTA comprises systematic, multidisciplinary evaluation, taking in the description, examination, and appraisal of healthcare, as well as the short- or long-term economic, social and ethical implications directly or indirectly related to existing and newly introduced health technologies .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
